ZiMuZu
倾情奉献
翻译
草草
小酸奶还想再干九年!
翻译
团子祝组织生快
某茶要求快发九周年队服
翻译
丽丽芙
冬麟
翻译
某羽
木浅薰
时间轴
Kallen   兜兜兜爹
特效
宝宝   草草
电脑狂人
第二季
第一集
校对&总监
草草
后期
饿得慌
顾问
somehacker
加尔维斯顿和休斯顿的善后清理工作仍在继续
Cleanup is still under way in both Galveston and Houston
上周飓风艾丽西亚的袭击  造成了不小损失
due to the damage caused by Hurricane Alicia last week
预计数额已达数十亿
with storm costs projected into the billions.
1983年可能将成为德州损失最大的
1983 is shaping up to be the costliest hurricane season
一个飓风季
in Texas history.
到目前为止  死亡人数为21人
The death toll currently stands at 21
受伤人数已逾百人
with reports of hundreds injured.
红十字会...
The red cross...
你干什么呢
What are you doing?
-来跟我玩  -自己玩吧  我得上班
- Come play with me. - Play with yourself. I gotta work.
-你也得上班呢  -乔
- You gotta work. - Joe.
我现在看不进去代码
I can't look at code right now.
来嘛  跟电脑玩没意思
Come. It's not as much fun to beat the computer.
-我想跟你玩  -为什么
- I want to beat you. - Why?
熟悉敌人才更好玩
It's just better when you know your enemy.
-是爱着敌人吧  -得了
- Love your enemy. - Please.
赛车啊
Racing, huh?
-轻松赢你  -走着瞧
- Easy win. - We'll see.
乔  你耍赖
Joe, that's cheating.
胜利
Victory.
好吧  那重赛
Okay, rematch.
来嘛
Come on.
你做不到  是吗
Oh, you can't do it, can you?
你都不能安心坐下来玩五分钟
You can't just sit and play for five minutes.
抱歉  现在是不行
I'm sorry, I can't. Not right now.
我们得加紧完善巨人的新操作系统
We gotta keep working on the Giant's new OS.
计算机分销商展览转眼就到了  我们得准备好
COMDEX is closer than we think. We gotta be ready.
我们会准备好的
We will be.
来吧  就一局  求你
Come on, one more game, please?
别玩太久
Don't play all day.
1985年3月  20个月后
早上好  早上好
Well, good morning, good morning.
你整得到处都是  伙计
You're getting that shit everywhere, man.
有灰忍忍吧  我们必须扩大空间
Uh, pardon our dust, but expand we must.
-怎么回事  -没地方放电缆了
- What's going on? - We're running out of room for cables.
在到处找地方塞
We're stuffing them anywhere we can.
早上好
Morning!
-包括墙里  -好  好主意
- Including the walls. - Good, great idea.
这人上来就走F3
This guy just opened with F3.
为什么就没人会玩国际象棋
Why is everyone bad at chess?
象棋太难[硬]
Chess is hard.
我才硬呢
I'm hard.
视差刚才又崩溃了
Um, "Parallax" just crashed again.
真是的  查清原因
Oh, god. Find out why.
-莱夫  速度如何  -网慢成渣了
- Lev, how's our speed? - The networks are lagging like a bitch.
超载引发了许多故障
Lots of fritzing out from overload.
-小心  -我以为新装的电话线
- Heads up! - I feel like the new phone lines we installed
流量足够了
should be able to handle the volume.
不行  还是会延迟会掉线
No, there's still delay and drop.
好吧  是谁把大兵手办放微波炉里的
Okay, who put stormtrooper in microwave?
阿基  辅助局域网中午前得弄好  行吗
Oh, Arki, I need the aux lan online by noon, okay?
-没问题  -天哪  受不了
- No problem. - Oh, god, this is gross.
莱夫  能检查一下电路吗
Hey, Lev, can we check the wiring?
好的
Yeah, sure.
重新加载视差  我先把用户
I'm redirecting users over to "Tank Battle"
引到坦克大战上去
while we reload "Parallax."
给我15分钟
Give me about 15 minutes.
这东西重启简直堪比启动游艇
Getting this thing live again is like launching a yacht.
谁能撤销一下主菜单吗
Can someone please deactivate the top menu item?
我不希望用户为了想进入一个
I don't want users blowing the system
已经下线的游戏挤爆系统
trying to enter a game that isn't there.
是我在爆系统
I'm blowing the system.
该死
Oh, shit.
怎么了  怎么了
What? What is it?
兄弟
Dude!
撞到一个门柱
Went through a stud.
太棒了  咱们的保证金没了
Great, there goes our security deposit.
那早就要不回来了  伙计们
We said good-bye to that a long time ago, boys.
穆特尼技术支持
Mutiny support.
你好  我叫切特·詹森  用户句柄极限极客
Hi, my name is Chet Jensen, user handle Kickassasaurus.
我想报告一个视差游戏的程序错误
I'd like to report a programming error in "Parallax."
那个有一堆镜子的走廊没有门
The narrow hall with a bunch of mirrors has no door.
不  那些不是镜子  是全息图
No, not mirrors, holograms.
我糊涂了
Oh, flummoxing.
但如果我说"看全息图"
But if I say, "Look at hologram,"
它就会说"你看到一个物体  但那不是实物"
it just says, "You see an object, but it isn't real."
-你碰得到吗  -不行  这上面说
- Okay, can you touch it? - Hmm, no, it says,
"你把手伸入光束中  但却抓不到"
"You put your hand into the light, but cannot grasp it."
-而且没法出去  -你好好想想
- And there's no way out. - Okay, well, think about it.
如果你能把手伸入全息图里  那说明了什么
If you can put your hand in the hologram, what does that mean?
你得思考一下
I mean, you have to think about
那个房间的物理空间结构
the physical space of the room, you know?
记住  那些安卓男巫
And remember, the Android sorcerer
阴险狡诈  诡计多端
is brilliant and cunning.
-伙计们  -弗洛斯蒂  别再拆螺丝了
- Guys! - Hey, Frosty, don't strip any more screws, okay?
我得把它们旋紧  旋得非常紧
Gotta-- gotta make 'em tight, real tight.
上帝啊  我们必须得重新布线
Oh, my God, we have got to rewire this.
造机柜都来不及
We can't build the cabinets fast enough.
还说什么布线啊
Wiring's an afterthought.
-上帝啊  -等等
- Oh, boy. - Wait just a darn minute.
我是可以穿过全息图吗
Can I walk through the hologram?
-也许哦  -妈妈咪呀
- Maybe. - Holy cow!
想出这个主意的人简直是天才
Whoever came up with that is brilliant.
谢谢  是我想出来的
Thank you. I came up with that.
-你是视差的开发者  -网络问题
- You're the creator of "Parallax"? - Network problem.
-严重延时  -好事啊  说明我们很受欢迎
- Serious lag. - That's good, we're popular.
不  我不知道服务器主机能不能承受得住压力
No, I don't know that the server host can handle the strain
连调制解调器组都不一定承受得住这种负载
or even if the modem bank can stay up with the load.
-去他妈的双陆棋  -谢谢
- Then screw backgammon! - Thank you.
怎么回事
What is going on here?
你们几个给我住手
You guys, cut it out.
视差老是崩溃
"Parallax" keeps crashing
就是因为他那版本的双陆棋太大了
because his version of backgammon is too big.
-怎么可能  -有多大
- No frickin' way! - Well, how big is it?
超过500K
Over 500k.
为什么一个双陆棋要花上半兆
Why does backgammon have to be half a meg?
不就是个有圆形棋子  三角形图案的方形棋盘吗
It's a square with some circles and some triangles.
-可能是因为颜色  -有颜色挺好的
- It could be all the colors. - Color is good.
拜托  我们做的是靠电话线传输的网络游戏
Hello, our games have to run on phone lines,
不是有塑料盒装内存的游戏机
not on a plastic cartridge with a crap ton of memory.
是啊  所以这游戏才这么烂
Yeah, and that's why they keep sucking.
这游戏不烂
Look, nothing sucks, okay?
视差老是崩溃
"Parallax" crashes all the time.
因为你装了一个巨大的双陆棋
Because you installed a big-ass version of backgammon.
听着  我们的问题不可能
Okay, look, backgammon cannot be the only reason
只出在双陆棋上  但在我们查清楚之前
that we're having problems, but until we figure it out,
悠悠球  把它重新编成灰度模式的吧
Yo-yo, just recode it and make it grayscale, okay?
什么  不行
What? No way!
怎么回事
What was that about?
我觉得我们得停机
I think we should unplug the cabinets.
想个更好的电源方案
Figure out a better power solution.
或许小心地把线重接一遍能改善延迟状况
Maybe rewiring everything more carefully will help with the lag.
你是说暂停网络服务吗
You mean take the network offline?
-对  停几小时  -我们不能那样做
- Yeah, for a couple hours. - We can't do that.
我们已经因为运行中断收到很多投诉了
We're already getting complaints about the outages.
如果我们不找出故障原因  只会变得更慢
It's only gonna get slower if we don't figure out what's wrong.
唐娜  不行
Donna, no.
你要玩什么
Whatcha playing?
有彩色的大游戏
Another fat-ass game with color.
我们烧了个断路器  是不是
We blew a breaker, didn't we?
我们不仅烧了断路器
We didn't blow the breaker.
好像整个街区都停电了
I think we blew the whole block.
我这就去看
Going.
你的工作是不是让你觉得无足轻重
Does your work have you feeling small and insignificant?
是不是无聊到手痒呢
Is it as boring as a hand full of beans?
给你的生活添加点冒险吧
Add adventure to your life.
爬上梯子  去发现卡迪夫电子的"巨人"系列
Climb that ladder and discover the Giant from Cardiff Electric--
个性化  便携  且物美价廉
Personal, portable, affordable.
现在向您介绍本系列的金牌产品
And now introducing the Giant's golden egg--
巨人专业版
The Giant Professional.
最高速度比IBM XT快三倍
Up to three times faster than the IBM XT.
拥有比苹果麦金塔更好的图像处理能力
And with better graphical capability than the Apple Macintosh,
巨人专业版可以带您的事业
The Giant Pro puts your business
走向巅峰
at the top of the stalk.
巨人专业版
早上好  我是奇普·劳莱特
Good morning, I'm Chip Rowlett
这里是《DFW财经》
with "DFW Moneyline,"
今天我们的嘉宾是戈登·克拉克
and I'm joined by Gordon Clark,
达拉斯支柱公司卡迪夫电子的现任总裁
current president of Dallas mainstay firm Cardiff Electric.
戈登  非常感谢你来到本节目
Gordon, thanks so much for being with us today.
谢谢你邀请我  奇普
Thanks for having me, Chip.
我们刚看到的是最新的全国广告
So what we just saw was the latest national spot
旨在推广卡迪夫电子过去两年内设计的
for two computers designed over the last two years
-两款电脑  -对
- by Cardiff Electric. - Uh, yes.
设计制造它们非常有趣
And that was a lot of fun to do--
但是个人电脑只是
But personal computing is
卡迪夫电子公司历史上的最新篇章
only the latest chapter in Cardiff's history.
而且  你本人
In fact, you yourself
对经营模式的改变就至关重要  对吗
were instrumental in the change to the business model, weren't you?
没错  没错  是的
Uh, yes. Yes, I was--
但现在卡迪夫电子要关门了  是吗
But now Cardiff is closing up shop?
也不是关门
Uh, well, not closing exactly.
我们没料到成功来得如此快
I guess we didn't expect so much success so quickly.
我们被一家海外大公司收购了
We've been acquired by a large overseas company.
但你还会继续留任总裁  是吗
But you will stay on as president, then?
你能不能...告诉他
Hi, could you just-- could you tell him...
其实  我觉得我也该翻篇了
Actually, I think it's time for me to move on.
我得去电力公司
I need to go to the power company.
-我得走了  -和朝九晚五说拜拜了吗
- I need to leave. - Oh, so, sayonara, 9:00 to 5:00, huh?
我认真考虑想创办一家自己的投资公司
Uh, I've given serious thought to starting my own investment firm...
在我的车库里创办
out of my garage.
有意思  为什么是车库
Interesting. Why the garage?
因为  奇普
Because, Chip, uh,
奇思妙想不会在董事会会议室诞生  对吧
good ideas don't come out of a boardroom, do they?
-很好  -说得好
- Very good. - That was good.
-我得走了  -那么  戈登  再次感谢
- Gotta go. - Well, Gordon, again,
你来到本节目
thanks so much for being with us.
我们还有许多商界信息要谈
We've got a lot more to talk about in the world of business,
广告之后  我们继续讨论
and we'll do that when we come back right after this.
谢谢  谢谢
Thanks. Thank you.
谢谢  戈登  干得好
Thanks, Gordon. Good job.
好了  我们两分钟后回来  赶紧
Okay, we're back in two, guys. Let's go.
德克萨斯州  奥斯汀
喂
Hello?
好
All right.
嗯
Yeah.
嗯  那太好了
Yeah, that's good news.
谢谢你
Thank you.
-是谁  -我的律师  出售完成了
- Who was that? - My attorney. The sale went through.
-真的吗  -他们要给我我的分成
- Really? - They're giving me my share.
太棒了  乔
That's fantastic, Joe.
我明天就去领
I gotta go up and pick it up tomorrow.
这太好了
This is good.
这是你挣来的  是你应得的
You earned this. You deserve it.
这毫无疑问
Don't doubt that for a second.
只是又要回去
Just-- just going back there,
见到那些人...
seeing those people...
我懂
I know.
你希望我取消今晚的聚会吗
You want me to cancel tonight?
我们不必请那些人来的
We don't have to have all these people over.
-不  -我们可以聊聊
- No. - We can just talk it through.
不  这能帮我分分心
No. It's a good distraction, yeah?
十公里
10 miles.
看得出来
I can tell.
好吧
Okay.
成为职场巨人
我是一名男性
Okay, so I am male.
我在娱乐圈工作
Uh, I am in entertainment.
有时是个歌手  对吧
Um, a singer sometimes, right?
-我已经死了  -据说你已经死了
- I'm dead. - Well, allegedly you're dead.
据说  好吧
Oh, allegedly. Okay.
该死
Damn it.
好吧  让我想想
Um, okay, let me think.
我是...他叫什么来着
I am-- oh, oh, what's his name?
是《出租汽车》的安迪·考夫曼吗
From "Taxi," Andy Kaufman?
终于猜到了
Finally!
我是安迪·考夫曼
I was Andy Kaufman.
我是大鸟  我们俩还挺配的
And I was big bird, so I guess we make quite the couple.
《芝麻街》人物
埃文在来的路上告诉我
Evan told me on the way over here
你们是在天文馆相遇的
that you two met at a planetarium?
你说吧
You tell it.
好吧  我们上学时就认识了
All right, well, um-- well, we knew each other in school.
但我们当时只是朋友
We were just friends, though.
我们是在修辞学课上认识的
We met in a rhetoric course.
我们总是争论不休
We argued all the time.
因为大部分时候你都错了
Well, 'cause you were wrong most of the time.
毕业后我们就失去了联系
I mean, we kind of lost touch after school.
你们也知道  去年我过得不太顺利
And as you guys know, last year was a rough year for me.
不管怎样  《德州月刊》派我去
Anyway, this assignment came through from "Texas Monthly"
了解菲斯克天文台  在那儿住一段时间
to go profile Fiske Observatory, to live up there for a while,
而那个时候  出差对我来说是件好事
and getting out of town seemed like a good thing to me at that point,
所以我去了  开始报道他们的SETI项目
so I did, and I started writing about their SETI program,
搜寻地外文明计划
Search for extraterrestrial intelligence.
对  对
Yep, yep.
于是我就在那儿探索太空  等待信号
And so there I was, searching the skies, waiting for contact.
-然后乔  -乔从门口走了进来
- And Joe... - Then joe walked through the door.
你做什么工作  乔
What do you do, Joe?
我在IBM工作过很长时间
I worked at IBM for a long time
然后又来到德州做个人电脑
and then I was in personal computers here in Texas.
-后来辞职了  -为什么
- And then I got out of it. - How come?
我需要重新考虑
I needed to reevaluate.
当时我以为我是对项目不满意
At the time, I thought I was unhappy with the project,
但后来我意识到我是对自己不满意
but in hindsight I realized I was just unhappy with myself.
这应该就是我一直忙于解决的事吧
So I guess that's what I've been working on.
乔太谦虚了
Well, Joe is being very modest.
他没告诉你们
What he didn't tell you
他几乎一夜之间把一家地域性的小公司
is he took this tiny regional company and
变成了有全国性竞争力的个人电脑公司
turned it into a national competitor for PCs almost overnight.
他明天要开车去达拉斯
He's driving up to Dallas tomorrow
领取公司出售他得到的分成
to collect his share of the company sale.
-但事情没这么简单  -确实
- But that's not the whole story. - No, it-- it's not.
但结局就是如此
But the outcome is the same.
那么你打算用这些钱来做什么
So what are you gonna do with all that dough?
我要成立一家自己的公司
I'm going to start my own company.
太棒了  在这里吗
That's great. Here?
不  去加利福尼亚
No, in California.
-硅谷  -什么
- In Silicon Valley. - What?
你们要搬家吗
Oh, you're moving?
还没定下来
Nothing is written in stone.
不过我们真的很期待
But we're really excited.
我想说的是  过去就让它过去吧
My point is, the past is past,
我们还有更美好的明天
but tomorrow is tomorrow.
真荒唐
This is ridiculous.
不知道雅达利会不会也这样断电
I wonder how often the power goes out at Atari.
总算来电了
Oh, finally.
好吧  那是什么
Okay, what is that?
卡梅伦解决了我们的供电问题
Uh, Cameron fixed our power problem.
是啊  我们把延长线
Yeah, we just ran extension cords
接到了邻居家的室外插座上
to the outdoor sockets next door.
好吧  拜托告诉我  你得到安德森家的准许
Okay, please tell me that you asked the Andersons' permission
才借用他们家的电
to siphon off their meter.
唐娜  安德森家富得流油
Donna, the Andersons are loaded.
涓滴理论  体制中给予上层人的利益
会传递给较低阶层的人
就当做是"涓滴"电力好了
Think of it as trickle-down electricity.
这问题可能比你想得要大
This is a bigger problem than you might think.
达拉斯电力公司知道我们的断路器超负荷了
Dallas Power & Light knows that we overrode our circuit breaker.
城市规划部可能正拿着告知我们
City planning is probably on its way with a notice
这栋房子不可作商用的通知赶来
saying that the house isn't zoned for commercial use.
我们将面临各种罚款
We're facing all kinds of fines,
所以我们最好还是不要再犯法了
so it would be really great if we stop breaking more laws
鉴于我们已经违反很多法规了
on top of the ones we've already broken.
唐娜  电力就是能量
Donna, power is power
而且我们能应付罚款  行吗
and we can handle the fines, okay?
唯一要解决的问题是延迟
The only real issue is the lag
我们得用更多网络设备和电脑来解决
and we can fix that with more network equipment and PCs.
我今晚打给我朋友
I'll call my guy tonight and
看他仓库里是不是还有XT
see if he has any more XTs in the warehouse.
-问题解决了  -那样治标不治本
- Problem solved. - Okay, that's a patch, not a fix.
是的  我们就需要先治标
Yes, which is what we need
好撑到真正治本
to hold us over until we can fix it for real.
电力公司在一号线
Power company on line one.
让我去接吗
Do you want me?
获奖者是F·穆雷·艾伯拉罕The winner is F. Murray Abraham.
85年奥斯卡最佳男主角
获奖影片为《莫扎特传》
真是的
Shoot,
艾迪·墨菲的《比弗利山警探》才该获奖
Eddie Murphy should've won for "Beverly Hills Cop."
《莫扎特传》主角
嫉妒莫扎特的宫廷乐师
安东尼奥·萨列里
我都不知道那个萨列里是谁
I don't know who that Salieri is.
问题就在这儿
That's the whole point.
他不是莫扎特
He's not Mozart.
-两杯啤酒  -红方威士忌  加冰
- Two shiners. - Walker red, rocks.
-记在他账上  -是啊  我们都失业了
- Put it on his tab. - Yeah, we're unemployed.
-老兄  -斯坦
- Hey, man. - Hey, Stan.
别理他们几个
Don't worry about those guys.
他们并不是真的失业了
They're not actually unemployed.
拉里要去坦迪公司面试  艾德可能会去EDS
Larry's interviewing at Tandy and Ed's likely going to EDS.
他大概就是有些恼火
He's probably just pissed
因为他要去一家叫"艾德家"的地方工作
'cause he'll be at a place called "Ed's,"
但他却不是老板
but he won't own it.
听懂了吗  艾德家
Get it? Ed's?
嗯  我听懂了  斯坦
Yeah, no, I got it, Stan.
但你得明白
But you have to understand that
我们并不是故意想破坏...
we weren't intentionally trying to damage it--
游戏厅刚上了台"挖金子"
Hey, they just got "Dig Dug II" at the arcade.
-实地考察去喽  -听着
- Research trip. - Look, I
我知道我们用了很多  可是  好  我等着
know that we use a lot, but-- yes, I'll hold.
太好了  伙计们  等等我
Amazing! Hey, guys, wait up.
-准备好了吗  -嗯
- Ready to do it? - Yeah.
-唐娜  -副驾
- Donna? - Shotgun!
-想一起去吗  -什么  不
- Do you want to go with them? - What? No.
不行  我得处理好这事
No, I have to take care of this anyway.
你想去的话  不必等他们来问你
If you want to go, you don't have to wait for them to ask.
跟着去就行了
You can just go.
是吗  那谁来应付电力公司
Oh, yeah? Then who's gonna deal with the power company?
不知道  让他们寄账单来  会处理好的
I don't know. Let them send a bill. It'll take care of itself.
好办法  你这个体系真好
That's great. That's a really amazing system you've discovered.
-有问题吗  -是的  卡梅伦  有问题
- Do you have a problem? - Yeah, cameron, I do.
你说这里没有老板
You made this a place without a boss,
虽然听上去很不错  但这样一来
and that sounds really nice, but what that translates into
只会造成一堆麻烦没人管
is a bunch of crap falling through the cracks
最后还得我来收拾
that I end up having to deal with.
天啊  既然你这么在行
God, well, if you're so good at dealing with it,
那就继续充当
then why don't you just keep being
我们都离不开的救世主好了
the savior we all supposedly need so much?
因为我不想当这里的家长
Because I don't want to be the mom here.
我在家已经是家长了
Look, I do that at home.
我来这儿是为了做我热爱的工作
I came here to do what I love,
-但我并不喜欢应付电力公司  -唐娜
- and I don't love dealing with the power company. - Donna.
我不喜欢管支票簿
And I don't love managing the checkbook
好保证我们不透支
to make sure we don't overdraw
我也不喜欢给一群程序员做奶妈
and I don't love playing wet nurse to a bunch of coders
他们简直像幼儿园小孩...
who act more like kindergarteners--
那就别做啊  没人要你去做
Then don't do those things! Nobody asked you to!
-天啊  -该死
- Jesus. - Damn it.
我已经尽力维持了  但内森...
I did everything I could to keep things going, but Nathan--
内森想卖掉
Nathan wanted to sell.
我拼命想保住大家的饭碗的  真的
You know, I fought for everyone's jobs, I really did.
你不必为从出售中得到很多钱而道歉
You don't have to apologize for making out like a bandit in the sale.
天啊
Oh, god.
如果我是你也会这么做
Man, I'd have done the same thing if I were in your shoes.
你接管之前  我还在升级系统软件包呢
Before you took over, I was updating systems software packages.
你来了之后
After you,
我们在两年内从零搭建了两台机器
we built two machines in two years from the ground up.
专业版就是巨人加点东西
The pro was just a Giant with a bag on the side of it.
专业版很棒  巨人很棒
The pro was amazing. Giant was amazing.
如果不是你
I would never have gotten
我根本没有机会参与其中
the opportunity to do any of it if it weren't for you.
还记得有天晚上  你找不到音乐来源吗
Gosh, you remember that one night when you couldn't find the music?
-什么  -记得吗
- What? - Remember?
当时我们调试专业版都三周了
We were three weeks deep on debugging the pro.
那天大概是凌晨4点吧  我们在"杀戮室"
It was maybe 4:00 am. We're in the Kill Room.
你无法专心工作  因为你认定
You couldn't focus because you were convinced
有人在停车场公放《梦想编织者》
somebody was cranking "Dream Weaver" in the parking lot.
-于是你出去看  -什么
- So you go out to check-- - What?
是啊  你出去看了
Yeah, you go outside, you check,
然后你又回来  拆掉一块天花板
You come back in, you take a ceiling tile out,
爬到天花板上
and you climb up into the ceiling.
记得吗  想一想  很逗的
Remember? Come on, it was amazing.
是啊
Yeah.
嗯  我...
Yeah, I...
大概是吧
Sort of.
是什么时候的事
When was this?
我记得是你
I mean, I think it was you.
我们当时为赶工嗑了那么多可卡因
Jesus, we were all so coked out of our minds trying to hit those deadlines.
谁知道呢
Who knows?
知道吗  唐娜  我觉得这挺不错
You know, Donna, I'm feeling really good about it.
这真是这一篇章最好的结局
I mean, this really is the best way that this chapter could've ended.
-能给我...  -给  加了奶油  两块糖
- Can I have-- - Here, cream, two sugars.
-谢谢  -现在我有时间了
- Oh, thank you. - Now I got time.
时间真是重要的宝贵资源
And time is such a valuable, precious resource.
-而现在我有大把时间  -是啊  真好
- And now I got boatloads of it, you know? - Yeah, that's great.
我可以开始搞投资  并且...
I can start this investment thing and--
-我的钥匙呢  -沙发上
- Oh, my keys? - Couch.
-看看灯旁边的靠枕底下  -谢谢
- Try the cushion by the lamp. - Thank you.
但我要先把钱花在孩子们身上
But you know what I'm gonna spend it on first is our kids.
我知道这话我说了很久了
And I know I've been saying that for a long time,
但这次我是认真的
But this time I really mean it.
你知道
I mean, did you know that
琼妮能唱整首《你好裘德》吗
Joanie can sing all the lyrics to "Hey, Jude"?
那多棒啊
I mean, I'm sorry, isn't that incredible?
-等等  女儿们呢  -简直不可思议...
- Wait, where are the girls? - It's absolutely phenom--
-穿好衣服了  在车里呢  -那就好
- They're dressed an in the car. - Oh, good.
-天呐  -怎么了
- Oh, my god. - What?
卡迪夫关门  戈登  是今天
The closing-- Gordon, it's today.
-我完全忘了  -没事  没事
- I completely forgot. - It's okay, it's okay.
我就打算过去  然后签字
Look, I'm just gonna go in. I'm gonna sign my name.
-不是什么大事  -还能拿到一大笔钱
- It's not a big deal. - And collect an incredible amount of money.
你真的做到了  你付出那么多努力
You really did it. You worked so hard.
-我真为你骄傲  -嗯
- I'm really proud of you. - Yeah.
看啊  他们这轮坦克大战15分钟前就结束了
Look at this. Their "Tank battle" round timed out 15 minutes ago
可他们还在用对话框说话
and they're still talking to each other in the chatbox.
还有用户聊得更久呢
Well, I've seen users do it longer.
他们一小时付5块钱
They're paying five bucks an hour
就在这儿聊春假要做什么吗
just so they can talk about what they're doing over spring break?
我要去见卖XT的人
Hey, I'm gonna go meet my XT guy.
-你能行吧  -嗯
- You good? - Yeah, I'm fine.
好
Good.
当然了
Of course.
你还来取你的分成
Of course you'd show up for your piece of the pie.
受不了
Unbelievable.
为保证效率  我要念股东的名字
To keep this efficient, I'll be calling out shareholders,
从最大的开始
starting with the largest first.
听到自己名字  就请进入会议室
Once you hear your name, please enter the conference room,
签署我们给你准备好的文件
sign the documents we've laid out for you,
然后就能拿到支票
and you'll receive your checks.
罗纳德  弗兰克  还有加勒特·卡迪夫
Ronald, Frank, and Garrett Cardiff.
你收到我的信了吗
Did you get my letter?
香格里拉怎么样
How was Shangri-la?
很好  很健康
It's good. Healthy.
桑宁代尔控股有限公司代表
Representatives of Sunningdale Holdings, limited.
内森这么早就卖公司是个错误
Nathan's making a mistake selling off so soon.
公司至少比这个估价高20%
Company's worth at least 20% more than this valuation.
我觉得烧掉一车
Well, I think it was a mistake
我们公司的电脑
to burn a truck full of our computers
然后跑去森林里也是错误呢
and then go running off into the woods.
好多的错误啊
A lot of mistakes.
是啊  很多
A lot, yeah.
很多错误
A lot of mistakes.
尼古拉斯·蒙迪地产
The estate of Nicholas Mundy.
说实话  我很高兴这都结束了
You know, honestly, I'm just glad it's over.
去年真是太折磨了
I mean, last year was a grind.
跟以前完全不一样
I mean, nothing like it was before.
不过以前也并不好玩
Although that wasn't much fun either.
第二台机器完全是重复工作
Second machine was a lateral move.
没那么有创意
Less inspired.
新东家都不想要那些机器
The new owners didn't even want the machines,
他们只想要专利
they just wanted the patents
好搭建更好的东西
so they could build something better.
专业版也没那么糟
The pro wasn't that bad.
没那么糟
Not that bad.
应该把这话写在包装上
We should've put that on the box.
戈登·克拉克
Gordon Clark?
在这里签字
And... sign right there.
-内森  -在第三页签字就好
- Nathan. - Just sign on page three.
我可以直接拿去银行兑换吗
So I can just take this to the bank?
是的  支票还是那么用的
Yes, that's still how checks work.
好了  合作愉快
All right, then. Thanks for the memories.
乔·麦克米伦
Joe MacMillan.
请坐
Just sit there.
在第三页签字
And just sign on page three.
这是你的分成  减去你烧掉的第一批货
This is your cut minus the first shipment that you burned.
你什么都别想得到
You get nothing.
一分没有
Not one red cent.
你要是想  就去告我吧
Now, you go ahead and you sue my ass if you want to
我是十分乐意
because I'd love nothing better
跟陪审团解释你都干了什么好事
than to tell a jury what you did here.
你毁了别人的生活
You destroy lives.
你让数十名老实正直的好人失去饭碗
You cost dozens of good, honest people their jobs.
你害我的销售部高级副总裁
You sent my SVP of sales,
我朋友约翰·博斯沃思进了监狱
my friend John Bosworth, to prison,
为了什么
and for what?
显示屏花哨  却百无一用的电脑
A doorstop of a computer with a fancy screen
毫无历史价值
and no legacy.
有些人说这次出售很成功
Some folks say this sale's a success.
我父亲大概会说
I think my father would've called it
这就是阉割公牛
cutting the nuts off of a bull and turning it into a steer.
你现在退出市场也好
It's good you're getting out now.
什么
What?
巨变要到来了
Something's coming.
势不可挡  而且不会带上这里
It's gonna be big and it won't include this place.
更不会带上你
And it certainly won't include you.
你个自以为是的混蛋
You entitled little bastard.
你要是乐意
You just keep going on
就继续相信自己的鬼话吧
believing your own bullshit if you need to,
但你永远都是那个自私
but you're always gonna be the same selfish
混蛋的骗子  只想捞一把
son-of-a-bitch rustler trying to get his.
你保重  内森
You stay healthy, Nathan.
话说
So...
你打算怎么用你的分成
what are you gonna do with your share?
不知道
I don't know.
你呢
You?
我大概会回车库去
I think I'm probably gonna head back into the garage, you know?
干点实事
Get my hands dirty.
好啊
Good for you.
你是个建造者  你就该搭建点什么
You're a builder. That's what you should do.
多谢你的信了
Thanks for the letter.
你说我想来就可以来的
You said that I didn't have to wait to be asked.
莱夫告诉我你在哪的
Lev told me where you were.
他总是迟到
He's always late.
我就是...
Oh, I was just--
我本该跟戈登去吃饭庆祝的
I was supposed to go to dinner with Gordon to celebrate.
什么事
What?
他在卡迪夫的最后一天了
Oh, it's his last day at Cardiff.
真想看那里被拆掉
Love to see a wrecking ball swing through that place.
来了
Oh, here we go.
你怎么认识这人的
How do you know this guy again?
他玩视差  卖二手设备
You know, he plays "Parallax," sells secondhand equipment.
好吧  他是黑市贩子
Fine, he's a fence.
二位美女
Mamacitas.
东西带来了
The gear is here.
我能看看吗
Do you mind if I...?
你说要XT  我就弄到了
You said XTs, I got XTs.
嗯
Yeah.
这位大妈怎么回事
What's with Mrs. Garrett?
-你说什么  -她挺好的
- Excuse me? - She's cool.
都已经挺旧的了
They're both pretty banged up.
这台显示卡都没了
I mean, this one doesn't have either of its video cards.
但我们还有余的呢  是吧
Yeah, but we have more, right?
这东西又不难找
Yeah. They're not hard to find.
我只是说价格该便宜点
I'm just saying that the price should come down a little.
这是零售  不是批发
This is retail, not wholesale.
这东西还是偷的呢
Oh, well, technically they're stolen.
唐娜  你怎么回事啊
Donna, what is wrong with you?
要不要XT了
You want the XTs or not?
我可以插电看看吗
Do you mind if I plug these in?
我带了逆变器
I brought a power inverter.
不可以
Yeah, I do mind.
好吧  我们要了
Yeah, okay, we'll take them.
三千
Three grand.
五百
500.
这东西销售价是7500呢
These things list for 7,500 each.
我们又没去商店买
Yeah, we're not paying list.
你俩挺大胆啊  就俩女人单独出来
That's pretty ballsy, the two of you out here alone.
是啊
Yeah.
好吧
Okay.
给
Here you go.
二位回头再找我啊
You ladies look me up post-Armageddon.
尤其是你  大妈
Especially you, Mrs. Garrett.
听上去是好用的
Well, it sounds functional.
搞什么
What the hell?
等等  给我手电
Hang on. Flashlight.
是仿造品
It's a counterfeit.
那能用吗
Can we still use them?
你会用中文编码吗
Can you code in Chinese?
他骗了我们
He ripped us off.
好吧
Okay.
妈妈不来了  是吗
Mommy isn't coming, is she?
嗯  妈妈又得加班了
No, mommy's got to work late again.
我们还是可以去庆祝的啊
Hey, we could still go celebrate.
你们晚餐想吃冰淇淋吗
Y'all wanna go get some ice cream for dinner?
想去布拉姆冰淇淋店吗
Y'all wanna go to Braum's?
-好啊  -想吃什么都行
- Yeah! - Whatever you want?
-好啊  -好  我们走
- Yes! Yes! - Yeah, all right! Let's go.
我们去吃香草冰淇淋
We'll get some vanilla ice cream,
加软糖香蕉
hot fudge, and bananas.
好棒
Yes!
爸爸  我们现在有钱了吗
Daddy, are we rich now?
我不知道该怎么回答你  亲爱的
I'm not quite sure how to answer that question, sweetheart.
我们是百万富翁了吗
Well, are we millionaires?
接下来四五年如果投资得当
With some smart investments in the next four or five years,
嗯  有可能的
yeah, we certainly could be.
我们可以买大象吗
Can we buy an elephant?
或许吧
Maybe.
理论上是可以的
I mean, theoretically.
那能吗
So, can we?
你不能只买一只大象
Well, you never wanna get just one elephant.
大象是很敏感的动物  如果只买一只
Elephants are sensitive creatures and if you just get one,
它会觉得孤单的
then it'll get lonely.
所以至少得买两只
You got to get at least two elephants.
老实说  亲爱的
And, frankly, sweetheart,
我觉得咱家地方不够大
I don't think we have the room.
既然我们都有钱了
If we're rich now,
那妈妈怎么还工作到那么晚
then why does mommy have to work so late?
知道吗  问得有道理
You know what? That's a good question.
爸爸  你的鼻子
Daddy, your nose.
爸爸
Daddy!
老天  我没事
Oh, my god. I'm okay.
我没事  乖乖  我就回来
I'm okay, girls. I'll be right back.
天呐  我记得我第一次见你时
Jesus, I remember the first time I met you,
你就像狄乐百货产品名录上的商务女性
just a perfect Dillard's catalogue businesswoman
看什么都不顺眼
with big judging eyes.
我才没有
Oh, I wasn't judging.
我只是看戈登看惯了
I'm just used to looking at Gordon.
这混蛋在哪
Oh, where is this asshole?
-你不也一样吓人  -才没有
- You're just as intimidating. - No.
你就是的  你还以此为傲
You know you are. You pride yourself on it.
记得我们推出网络的时候吗
You remember when we launched the network?
花了四天时间才成功上线
It took four days straight to get it live.
就像搭谷仓一样困难
It was like raising a barn.
视差从菜单上启动不了
And "Parallax" wouldn't boot from the menu.
到一半的时候
You know, halfway through,
我们都以为是成不了了
a bunch of us thought it was never gonna happen.
我们完了  穆特尼还没开始就完蛋了
We were done. Mutiny was over before it even started.
但你不这么想  你没放弃
But not you. You didn't give up.
嗯  是挺不容易
Yeah, well, it was intense.
那么
So...
你觉得我该当老板
You think I should be the boss.
我觉得该有人当老板
I think someone should be.
我知道我们现在也挺好
Look, I know we're doing fine,
但现在就是大多数我们这样的公司倒闭的时候了
but this point right now is when most companies like us go under.
我们发展停滞了
We're plateauing.
我们得发展壮大起来  否则就没戏了
We need to grow in a big way or we're not gonna make it.
好吧  那是不行的
Okay, well, we can't let that happen.
我们急需很多重要必需品
We're in dire need of some major essentials.
我们需要更多用户  我们的订阅已经达到极限了
We need more users. Our subscriptions have topped out.
我们需要新游戏
We need another game.
我们都六个月没发布新东西了
We haven't put anything out in, what, six months.
我知道  唐娜  但我得等最佳的点子
Yes, I know, Donna, but I need to wait for the right idea.
而且我们得扩张网络
And we need to expand the network
光靠买偷来的XT已经不够了
because buying stolen XTs isn't gonna cut it anymore.
你说得对
You're right.
你说得都对
You're-- yes, you're totally right.
但是
But here's the thing. I--
我不想当家做主
I'm not interested in being in charge.
我想工作  做我喜欢做的
I want to work, I want to do my thing.
我不想做产品管理
I'm not interested in product managing.
我也一样
Well, I'm not either.
我注意到用户玩游戏时
Look, I've been watching people chat on the network
在线上聊天  有时候游戏打完还能聊几个小时
while they're playing, sometimes even after for hours on end,
我觉得完全可以借此
and I think there's a real opportunity
在游戏之外建立一个社区
for a community to exist outside the games.
如果你帮我一起管理
So if you just help me with the managerial side,
我就可以做做这方面
then I can play around with that
同时继续管理网络
and still keep my hands in the guts of the network
这样我就很开心了
and I'm a happy camper.
死混蛋
Son of a bitch.
混蛋
Hey, dickhead.
你卖给我们的电脑是仿造品
Those computers you sold us were counterfeits.
真遗憾
Bummer.
我们想要回我们的钱
We want our money back.
抱歉  女士们
Sorry, ladies.
不行  五百  掏出来
Uh, no, 500 on the bar now.
过来
Come here.
-乔  -好了
- Joe! - Okay!
好了  抱歉打扰你了
Okay, okay, we're sorry we bothered you.
再见
Good-bye.
好了
Okay.
我们的好运也该到头了
Well, I think we pushed our luck about as far as it's gonna go.
什么
What?
你怎么...
How did you--?
这混蛋有两台崭新的XT  还没开箱呢
Hey, that little shit has two brand-new XTs back here in boxes.
什么
What?!
别拿钱了  拿走装备
Leave the money, just grab the gear.
开车门
Open the trunk!
给我
Give it to me.
我抱住了
Okay, I got it.
小偷
Scavengers!
你还想要我的电话吗
Hey, you still want my number?
搞什么
What the hell?
你没事吧
You all right?
嗯
Yep.
你的鼻子怎么了
What happened to your nose?
过敏
Allergies.
你没赶上晚饭
We missed you at dinner.
是啊  真抱歉
I know, I'm sorry.
没事
It's fine.
等我下次卖公司我们再去吧
We'll just go out next time I sell a company.
-你喝醉了吗  -我没事
- Are you drunk? - I'm fine.
工作...工作上的事闹得很疯
Work just went-- oh, I don't know. Work went insane.
我给你留了一块布拉姆的山核桃派
I got you a slice of Braum's pecan pie.
放冰箱里了
It's in the fridge.
谢谢  我留着行吗
Thanks. You mind if I just save it?
我累死了  我要去睡了
I'm exhausted. I'm gonna go crash.
嗯
Yeah, sure.
唐娜
Hey, Donna?
怎么了
Yeah?
这挺好的吧
This is good, right?
卖掉卡迪夫  向前看
Selling Cardiff, you know, moving on.
挺好的吧
Right?
嗯  挺好的
Yeah, it's very good.
嗯  我就是...
Yeah, I just...
而且  这本来也由不得你
And besides, it wasn't up to you.
我都有点担心了
I was getting worried.
一切顺利吗
Did everything go okay?
昨晚晚餐时
At dinner last night...
你说我的那些话  是真心的吗
Do you believe those things you said about me?
当然了
Of course I do.
我是保留了些没说出来
Yes, I left some details out.
我没说你伤害到了很多人
I didn't say that you hurt a lot of people
也没说你是靠撒谎进了门
or that you lied your way through the door,
但那家公司的今天是你造就的
but you made that company what it is today.
我没拿到钱
I didn't get the money.
他们把我赶走了
They shut me out.
我们不需要那笔钱
Well, we don't need the money.
嫁给我吧
Marry me.
什么
What?
-为什么  -因为我爱你
- Why? - Because I love you.
因为我是第一个原谅你的人吗
Or because I was the first person to forgive you?
我知道你害怕
I get that you're scared.
你以前也走过这条路
You've been down this road before.
嫁给我吧
Marry me.
好
Yes.
游戏结束
卡梅豪伊  玩得不赖  新用户吗
用户85  是啊  才订阅的